Finding aid of the Finding aid of the San Francisco AIDS Foundation (SFAF) Records
Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, Transgender Historical Society
- Media Relations, 1986-2002; Series 2; 32 folders
  - AIDS Walk San Francisco 2001, clippings (Box 2: 43)
  - AIDS Walk San Francisco 2002 (Box 2: 44)
- Newsletters, 1983-2005; Series 3; 50 folders
  This series contains newsletters created by various departments of SFAF throughout its history. The most comprehensive runs of newsletters are BETA and Positive News (English version) in the Education subseries. Of particular interest to researchers might be the very early newsletters in the General News and Publicity subseries.
  - Subseries 3.1 General News and Publicity, 1983-2005
    This subseries contains the earliest newsletter in the collection from the period when SFAF was still the AIDS/KS Foundation, Inc. Although not complete runs, they do provide valuable information about the climate at the time. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Advance: The Monthly Bulleting of SFAF, Dec. 1990-July 1992 (Box 3: 1 - 2)
    - AIDS and KS Foundation Newsletter, May 1983-June 1983 (Box 10)
    - Can WeTalk? (1 issue), Feb. 1984 (Box 3: 3)
    - OUTReach: News you can Use to Fight HIV/AIDS, Apr. 1997-Oct. 2005 (Box 10)
    - Report to the Community, Dec. 1983; Dec. 1984 (Box 10)
  - Subseries 3.2, Board of Directors, 1985-1998
    The newsletters in this subseries were targeted at major donors. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Impetus (later called SFAF News), Summer 1986-Winter 1993 (Box 3: 4 - 5)
    - SFAF News (formerly Impetus), Fall 1995-Summer 1998 (Box 3: 6 - 7)
  - Subseries 3.3, Education, 1988-2005
    This subseries documents SFAF's mission to create non-duplicative educational material. It also represents SFAF's outreach through its publication of Positive News in four languages. The newsletters in this subsereis primarily deal with HIV-health information. BETA is a technical/academic newsletter and Positive News is written for low literacy readers. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - AIDS Educator Catalog, Fall 1988 (Box 3: 8)
    - BETA Bulletin of Experimental Treatment for AIDS, 1988-2005 (Box 3: 9 - 25)
    - BETA en Espanol, 1992-2005 (Box 3: 26 - 39)
    - BETA Headline Treatment News, 1993-1998 (Box 3: 40)
    - Monthly Listing of AIDS-Related Educational Events (1 issue), Nov. 1988 (Box 4: 1)
    - Noticias Positivas [Positive News in Spanish], Spring 1991-July 1999 (Box 10:)
    - Positive News, Spring 1991-Fall 1993 (Box 4: 2)
    - Positive News, Dec. 1998-July 1999 (Box 10:)
    - Positive News [in Chinese], 1991-1993 (Box 4: 3)
    - Positively Pinoy [Positive News in Tagalog], 1994 (Box 10:)
    - Treatment Information, undated (Box 4: 4)
  - Subseries 3.4, People with AIDS Outreach, 1986-1987
    The newsletter in this subseries was a joint project with Shanti Project. It has an informal, upbeat style and provided information on workshops, taxes, social events, a classifieds section and other information for people with AIDS. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - People with AIDS Update, Feb. 1986-May 1987 (Box 4: 5)
  - Subseries 3.5, Public Policy, 1994-1998
    This subseries contains monthly newsletters focused on key HIV policy issues such as legislation and funding, state and federal HIV prevention reform efforts, the status of various federal health care reform initiatives, and specific information on how to get involved in advocacy efforts. Also included with some issues are background articles and clippings pertaining to topics in that issue. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - HIV Policy Watch, June 1994-Feb. 1998 (Box 4: 6 - 7)
    - San Francisco HIV Policy Watch, July 1996-July 1998 (Box 4: 8)
  - Subseries 3.6 Staff, 1996-1999
    This subsereis contains an all staff newsletter that was created to increase communication, and keep morale high. The focus of the newsletter is the staff. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - The Loop, Oct. 1996-Feb. 1999 (Box 4: 9)
  - Subseries 3.7, Other Organization's, 1985-1999
    This subseries contains newsletters published by individuals and organizations other than SFAF that were found in the collection. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - AIDS Treatment News, John S. James (1issue), Jan. 13, 1989 (Box 4: 10)
    - Coming UP! The Lesbian/Gay Community Calendar of Events and Newspaper for the Bay Area (1 issue), Dec. 1985 (Box 10:)
    - Mansex 101, Stop AIDS Project, Spring 1999 (Box 4: 11)
- Monographs, 1984-2006; Series 4; 90 folders
  This series contains monographs primarily created by various departments of SFAF. Included are research reports, papers, programs, brochures, and books.
  - Subseries 4.1 Board of Directors, 1985-2004
    This subseries provides general information about the activities and structure of SFAF. Through these, one can see the emergence, decline and merger of various departments. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Annual Report/Year in Review, 1985-2004 (Box 4: 12 - 21)
  - Subseries 4.2, Client Services, 1984-2001
    This subseries contains booklets and guides produced to help AIDS and ARC patients, friends, family and care-givers locate the proper medical, financial and emotional resources. They contain San Francisco resource listings in English and Spanish. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - AIDS and ARC: A Resource Manual, 1988 (Box 4: 22)
    - AIDS Medical Guide, 1988 (Box 4: 23)
    - Client Services Handbook, 1997 (Box 4: 24)
    - Coping with AIDS, 1984 (Box 4: 25)
    - The Family's Guide to AIDS, 1984 (Box 4: 26)
    - HIV Resource Guide (title varies), 1988-1998 (Box 4: 27 - 31)
    - HIV Resource Guide (English and Spanish), 1997-1998 (Box 4: 32)
    - Manual de Ayuda al Cliente, 1997 (Box 4: 33)
    - VIH: Guia de Recursos (title varies), 1995-2001 (Box 4: 34 - 35)
  - Subseries 4.3, Development, 1991-2006
    This subseries primarily contains programs and event guides from SFAF fundraisers. Perhaps the most valuable sources of information in this subseries are programs from SFAF's annual Leadership Recognition Dinner. These could potentially be important because they contain lists of SFAF boards of directors, donors, corporate and foundation partners, previous honorees, some histories of the organization, and biographies of individual and corporate awardees. One item of note is the 1996 Leadership Recognition Dinner program, which contains a copy of the speech given that year by Executive Director Pat Christensen. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - AIDS Walk/Marathon Mailings, 2000-2005 (Box 4: 36)
    - AIDS Walk San Francisco Event Guide, 1994-2002 (Box 4: 37 - 43)
    - AIDS Walk San Francisco Event Guide, 2003-2006 (Box 10)
    - California AIDS Ride 4, 1997 (Box 4: 44)
    - California AIDS Ride 4 Rider Portfolio Packet, 1997 (Box 4: 45)
    - Classical Action (title varies), 1995-1998 (Box 4: 46)
    - Leadership Recognition Dinner (invitation), 1991 (Box 5: 1)
    - Leadership Recognition Dinner, 1992-2006 (Box 5: 2 - 16)
  - Suberies 4.4, Education, 1986-2000
    This subseries contains internal education reports as well as monographs produced for distribution. One item of note is "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" a resource guide to safe sex practices for young (18-24) gay and bisexual men containing poetry and photographs by young gay and bisexual men. See the Photography series for all of the photographs submitted for acceptance to "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs". This series is arranged alphabetically.
    - BETA Readership Survey, 1994 (Box 5: 17)
    - Catalog of Educational Materials, 1986 (Box 5: 18)
    - An Epidemic of Loss: AIDS in San Francisco's Gay Male Community 1988-1993, 1987 (Box 5: 19)
    - The New Epidemic (4 part series in BAR), 2000 (Box 10:)
    - Primal Cream: An advanced Guide to Sexual Pleasure and Health, 1993 (Box 5: 20)
    - Positive News: An Evaluation of Readability, Content and Usefulness in English, Spanish, Tagalog and Chinese, 1994 (Box 5: 21)
    - Results from the 1994 BETA Readership Study (Box 5: 22)
    - sumt'n ta say/behind our backs [for young gay and bi men], 1995 (Box 5: 23)
  - Subseries 4.5, Public Policy, 1996-2000
    This subseries contains material created to inform and guide a grassroots network of individuals and organizations to advocate at all levels of governement for effective HIV-related public policy. Also included are policy agendas for CA and the nation, and a legislative report card for 1999. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Advocacy in an new Era: A Resource Manual for HIV/AIDS Advocates in a Time of Change and Hope, 1997 (Box 5: 24)
    - Advocacy in a new Era: Access to Treatment, Medicaid, ADAP and CARE, 1997 (Box 5: 25)
    - Every Voice Counts: A Grassroots Advocacy Manual for the HIV/AIDS Community, 2001 (Box 5: 26)
    - Giving Life a Home: HOPWA at work in San Francisco A Report on the Implementation of the Housing Opportunities for People with AIDS Program in San Francisco, California, 1997 (Box 5: 27)
    - Grassroots Lobbying, 1996 (Box 5: 28)
    - Grassroots Lobbying: A Guide for Advocates Concerned with HIV/AIDS, undated (Box 5: 29)
    - Grassroots Lobbying: A Guide for Advocates Concerned with HIV/AIDS [larger version], undated (Box 5: 30)
    - Grassroots Lobbying: A Guide for Citizens Concerned with HIV/AIDS, undated (Box 5: 31 - 32)
    - HIV/AIDS and Immigrants: A Manual for Service Providers, 2004 (Box 5: 33)
    - La Movilizacion Politica Popular, 1997 (Box 5: 34)
    - A New Era for HIV/AIDS Care, Treatment and Services: An Agenda for California Government 1997-1998 (Box 5: 35)
    - Making the Grade: The Legislative Report Card on HIV/AIDS, 1999 (Box 5: 36)
    - New Hopes, New Challenges: An HIV/AIDS Policy Agenda for San Francisco, 1998 (Box 5: 37)
    - One Voice can Make a Difference...Many Voices can Create A Movement: A Grassroots Advocacy and Community Organizing Manual for the HIV/AIDS Community, 2000 (Box 5: 38)
    - Renewing the Commitment: An HIV/AIDS Policy Agenda for the Nation, 1998 (Box 5: 39)
    - Toward 2000: An HIV/AIDS Policy Agenda for California, 1999 (Box 5: 40)
  - Subseries 4.6, Volunteer Services, 1992-1994
    - SFAF Staff Manual: Working with Volunteers, 1994 (Box 5: 41)
    - Staff and Volunteer Yearbook, 1992 (Box 5: 42)
  - Subseries 4.7, Created Outside SFAF, 1986-2004
    This subseries primarily contains research reports. There are some general monographs. This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Clinical and Legal Perspectives on Prenatal Drug and Alcohol Use: Guidelines for Individual and Community Response, Marty Jessup and Robert Roth, 1986 (Box 5: 43)
    - Management and Organizational Needs Assessment Study of U.S. AIDS Agencies, Prepared for the National AIDS Network, 1987 (Box 5: 44)
    - Presentation to the Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic. Panel 10: Outreach Education to Intravenous Drug Users, Harvey W. Feldman, 1987 (Box 5: 45)
    - Preventing Human Immunodeficiency Virus Contagion Among Intravenous Drug Users: The Impact of Street-Based Education on Risk-Behavior. Paper read before the III International Conference on AIDS, John K. Watters, 1987 (Box 5: 46)
    - Comprehensive Plan to Reduce the Spread of HIV Infection Among Injection Drug Users (IDUs) in the City and County of San Francisco, Raymond Baxter, 1992 (Box 5: 47)
    - Meanings, Complexities, and Condoms: Towards Understanding the Sexual Landscape of Middle-class Gay Men in San Francisco, A.M. Williams, circa 1994 (Box 5: 48)
    - Questions at the Crossroads: Surviving the Third Decade of HIV Infection in California, AIDS Partnership California, 2004 (Box 5: 49)
    - Sex, Drugs and HIV: A Sociocultural Analysis of two Groups of Gay and Bisexual Male Substance Users who Practice Unprotected Anal Sex, A.M. Williams, circa 1996 (Box 5: 50)
    - Stand up to be Counted: A Great City Must Respond to AIDS, [The Tides Foundation], undated (Box 5: 51)
    - Voices of C.A.R.E.: People Living with HIV and AIDS and the Ryan White Comprehensive AIDS Resources Emergency Act, AIDS Action Committee of Massachusetts, et. al, 2000 (Box 5: 52)
  - Subseries 4.8, Brochures, 1983-2004
    This series contains educational and informational brochures primarily put out by SFAF, many of which were available for purchase by other AIDS organizations. Of particular interest to researchers might be the very early brochures. This suberies is arranged chronologically by SFAF brochures, followed by brochures of other organizations.
    - Brochures, SFAF, 1983-1988 (Box 5: 53)
    - Brochures, SFAF, 1991-2004 (Box 5: 54)
    - Brochures, other organizations, 1987-1989; undated (Box 5: 55)
- Education, 1986-2005; Series 5; 20 folders
  This series documents some of the education outreach activities of SFAF. The most heavily represented activity is the development of educational ad campaigns.
  - Subseries 5.1, Targeted Groups, 1987-2005 (Box 11 folders)
    This subseries documents some of SFAF's efforts to identify at risk groups and develop educational campaigns and support programs that directly targeted and reflected the needs of these groups. This subseries illustrates their use of focus groups to develop and refine campaigns. One item of interest is a paper on the emergence of a gay identity in Latin America in the "Latino AIDS response" folder. Articles on cleaning hypodermic needles with bleach are also included. Types of materials include clippings, articles, handwritten notes, and correspondence. This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - "MidCity Consortium to Combat AIDS" [intravenous drug users], 1987-1988 (Box 6: 1)
    - Campaign for black gay men, 1988 (Box 6: 2)
    - "Latino AIDS response", 1988; undated (Box 6: 3)
    - "Latino AIDS Project" re. poster, 1990 (Box 6: 4)
    - Focus group report re. Compass Project, 1996 (Box 6: 5)
    - Focus group transcript re. Females, 1997 (Box 6: 6)
    - Vida y Movimiento, 1998 (Box 6: 7)
    - Black Brothers Esteem Leadership Institute (binder), 2000 (Box 6: 8 - 9)
    - Black Brothers Esteem, 2002-2005 (Box 6: 10)
  - Subseries 5.2, Campaigns, 1986-2003
    This series contians records documenting SFAF's educational campaigns. Included are images from campaigns, community program ideas, poster ideas and a video tape of commercials. This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - "AIDS: Fight the Fear with the Facts", 1986 (Box 6: 11)
    - HIV Prevention Series VHS (8 x :30 spots), circa 1990 (Box 9)
    - Castro Street Fair Ideas, 1994 (Box 6: 12)
    - Poster ideas, 1996; undated (Box 6: 13)
    - "Sex Drug Exchange", 2002 (Box 6: 14)
    - "Speed Project", circa 2003 (Box 6: 15)
    - "Gay Life", 2003 (Box 6: 16)
    - Castro Stop AIDS campaign ads, undated (Box 6: 17)
    - "Without a Condom You're a Dickhead" (foreign language), undated (Box 6: 18)
  - Subseries 5.3, Additional Education Documents, 1995-1998
    This subseries contains miscellaneous education documents. This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - List of events videos, SFAF (handwritten), circa 1995 (Box 6: 19)
    - Website project, SFAF, 1995-1998 (Box 6: 20)
    - Web/Internet general information, 1996-1997 (Box 6: 21)
- Administration, 1984-2005; Series 6; 7 folders
  This series contains a limited amount of financial records and a small amount of correspondence from executive directors. Items of note are the strategic plan and operating budget records because they contain organizational charts of SFAF, although the date range is limited. Also of note in this series is a draft of an opinion editorial piece written by Derek Gordon about hate crimes directed at SFAF and executive director Pat Christensen. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence from Executive Directors, 1984-1985; 1989 fix (Box 6: 22)
  - General histories of SFAF, 1989-2001 (Box 6: 23)
  - Strategic plan and operating budget, 1989; 1999-2005 (Box 6: 24)
  - Miscellaneous development/fundraising, 1989-2003 (Box 6: 25)
  - Financial report, 1993 (Box 6: 26)
  - Draft of opinion editorial piece to B.A.R., circa 1997 (Box 6: 27)
  - Report of audit of financial records, 2001-2005 (Box 6: 28)
- Photographs, 1986-2005; Series 7; 32 folders
  The majority of the photographs in this series are from sumt'n ta say/behind our backs. Items of note include photographs from Black Brothers Esteem. This series is arranged chronologically. Within sumt'n ta say/behind our backs folders are arranged alphabetically by photographer.
  - "AIDS: Fight the Fear with the Facts", 1986 (Box-folder 10)
  - "You Can't See Aids", 1987 (Box 7: 1)
  - Latino AIDS project, 1990 (Box 7: 2)
  - unidentified male, 1990 (Box 7: 3)
  - "Be Here for the Cure" I, 1992 (Box 7: 4)
  - "Sex is Good", 1992 (Box 7: 5)
  - "Be Here for the Cure II", 1993 (Box 7: 6)
  - "No Condom No Date", 1993 (Box 7: 7)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Mark Bridges, 1995 (Box 7: 8)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Carlos Garcia, 1995 (Box 7: 9)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Noe Gutierrez, 1995 (Box 7: 10)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Louis Guzman, 1995 (Box 7: 11)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Morgan Kirby, 1995 (Box 7: 12)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Derek Lassiter, 1995 (Box 7: 13)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Erickson Liongsam, 1995 (Box 7: 14)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Doug Natner (sp?), 1995 (Box 7: 15)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Hoang Nguyen, 1995 (Box 7: 16)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Carlos Penate, 1995 (Box 7: 17)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Richard Renfro, 1995 (Box 7: 18)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Michael Smith, 1995 (Box 7: 19)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" Jaime Soria, 1995 (Box 7: 20)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" unknown, 1995 (Box 7: 21)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" extra contact sheets, 1995 (Box 7: 22)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" prints used, 1995 (Box 7: 23-26)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" prints not used, 1995 (Box 8 1)
  - Black Brothers Esteem, 1998 (Box 8 2)
  - Black Brothers Esteem, 2005 (Box 8 3)
  - [by Leslie Hirsch], undated (Box 8 4-5)
  - unidentified male, undated (Box 8 6)
- Negatives, circa 1980s-1995; Series 8; 7 folders
  This series primarily contains negatives from submissions to sumt'n ta say/behind our backs. Other items of note include negatives from a Rubber Men event and some negatives from AIDS LifeCycle. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Rubber Men, circa 1980s (Box 8 7)
  - Unidentified party, circa 1980s (Box 8 8)
  - "Be Here for the Cure II", 1992 (Box 8 9)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" to box 7 folder 23, 1995 (Box 8 10)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" to box 7 folders 8-20, 1995 (Box-folder 6)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" to prints not used, 1995 (Box 8 11)
  - "sumt'n ta say/behind our backs" miscellaneous, 1995 (Box 8 12)
  - AIDS LifeCycle, undated (Box 8 13)
- Slides, circa 1983-circa 2000; Series 9; 1,644 slides
  This series has not been arranged.
  - Unidentified, circa 1983-circa 2000 (Box 9)
- Posters, circa 1980s-circa 2005; Series 10; 1 box
  This series contains approximately 15 small to oversize posters from various campaigns including "Be Here for the Cure II" and Black Brothers Esteem. Also included are approximately 7 framed items including brochures and photographs. One item of note is a foam core bleachman poster. This series has not been arranged.
  - Unidentified, circa 1980s-circa 2005 (Box-folder 10)
- Miscellaneous, 1997-2006; Series 11; 3 folders
  This series contains miscellaneous records related to cycling. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - "The Unknown Cyclist" a screenplay, 1997 (Box 6: 29)
  - Collected works of cheerleader Scott, AIDS LifeCycle, 2006 (Box 6: 30)
  - AIDS Ride speech, circa 1980s (Box 6: 31)